Empresses in the Palace—the Lengend of Zhen Huan
Adopted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Donate or join us: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Your Highness, Fuzi is dead.
Dead?
How come?
When did this happen?
Her swollen corpse was just pulled out of a well.
Do you not care about respecting taboos
in front of Her Highness?
It's all right.
That day, Her Highness scolded Fuzi
and she ran out of the chamber, crying.
She must have misstepped and stumbled in the dark.
So it's my fault?
Of course not.
It was her own fault for having such a bad temper.
All servants hear criticism sometimes.
Don't you agree, Jiang Fujiang?
Your Highness... I dare not voice my opinion.
What are you afraid of?
If you're in doubt, you can ask anyone in my palace
if they didn't see Fuzi running out
with their own two eyes.
Are you suggesting
that someone pushed her from behind?
I wouldn't dare.
But you did!
You can investigate each and every member of my palace
if you don't believe me.
Your Highness, that wasn't my intention.
Let me be more direct:
You're here at the Empress's behest
to investigate Fuzi's death.
You have asked. I have answered.
And there are witnesses.
You are permitted to take away my servants.
But if you trouble me again,
I won't be so kind.
Your Highness, I shall take my leave.
All of you, remember:
Fuzi ran out by herself.
She slipped and fell into the well.
Yes, sir.
My Lady, it smells so fragrant.
My Lady, you haven't eaten
after you had a shock yesterday.
You should at least eat something this morning.
A moment of fright doesn't matter.
What I'm worried about is
having to live in fear every day.
Why?
Attendant Xia was insolent,
and that shows how many enemies Meizhuang and I have.
Consort Fleur is imperious,
and her tactics are merciless.
With so many daggers poised
over my back and stomach,
it wouldn't matter if they prevailed over me,
but my whole family would suffer if I
received any punishment.
What should we do?
I don't know...
My Lady, do you remember how we often made
osmanthus flower honey at home?
Now that we have so many osmanthus flowers,
how about I marinate some in sugar?
Would you like that?
Your cooking is always delightful.
I will eat it if you make some.
Yes.
I'll get some help.
Violet, what are you looking at?
You look intrigued.
My Lady, Look. The ants are moving strangely.
They keep moving around the root of the crabapple tree.
They seem to be avoiding something.
I think the ants are stupid for taking such a long detour.
Xiao-Yunzi, dig around here and see what's underneath.
Understood.
What's this, buried so deep?
My Lady, there's a jar here.
Take it out.
What is it?
Pull harder.
Here, let me take a look.
Go away.
What a strange jar.
It has a strong scent.
It could be something that belonged to Noble Lady Parfum.
She was favored by the Emperor, but got banished to the
Cold Palace after her miscarriage.
Could it be some rare incense?
My Lady likes incense. Let's open the jar and have a look.
Here, give it to me.
Unwrap it.
It's so foul!
What a pungent smell!
It's just some cheap incense.
Jade, put it away.
You must not say anything about what we found today.
Yes.
We wouldn't want people gossiping about it.
Vermilion, let's have the osmanthus dessert tomorrow.
Everyone, disperse.
Go back to your work.
Jade, let's go inside.
Take it away.
What's wrong, My Lady? You look unwell.
I feel sick and flustered.
Jade, can you bring Dr. Wen here?
Remember, it has to be him.
Dr. Wen!
I'm glad you're on shift.
My Lady is not feeling well.
Please go and see her right away.
Is My Lady all right?
She told me that you have to be the one who examines her.
Please go quickly.
Yes.
My Lady, you had quite a fright.
I saw things I shouldn't have.
You should try to put them out of your mind.
Dr Wen, will you keep the promise
you made to me outside the temple?
Yes, I will forever put you before everything else.
"Forever" is easy to say
but hard to commit to.
I know I fall short elsewhere.
My only virtue is that I can keep a promise.
We met in childhood,
and your father's kindness to my family
will not be forgotten, even in my old and toothless days.
My Lady, I will do anything you ask.
I don't want to share the emperor's bed.
Although that is also what my heart desires,
since you have entered the palace, it is unavoidable.
For you life ahead, I hope you can
do it sooner, My Lady.
But I'm too scared
to serve His Majesty now.
Dr. Wen, I'd like to show you something.
How did this come into your possession, My Lady?
The crabapple tree in my courtyard
did not bloom this spring.
I accidentally discovered a jar under the tree.
I've heard of Lady Parfum's unexpected miscarriage.
I suppose this is the cause
and a trace of the fierce rivalries in the palace.
Lady Parfum might never have scented
the cause of her despair.
It was a timely discovery.
Otherwise, all the girls in your palace would have been affected.
Although I cannot spend my life beside you,
my promise will be fulfilled
if I can be the guardian of your welfare.
Is my illness serious?
The internal heat caused by the shock must be
treated emotionally.
It will be cured in half a month if you take care.
But if you wish, I'll prescribe a formula
for a gradual and comprehensive recovery.
Musk can cause miscarriage or infertility.
You shouldn't keep this near you.
Allow me find a purpose for it at the Imperial Infirmary
to make amends for its past crimes.
Dr. Wen...
I can't shake off my fear.
Don't be afraid.
Vermilion,
escort Dr. Wen out.
Yes.
Attendant Sourire is sick?
She was well yesterday.
The evil qi invaded her body and induced heart palpitations.
Attendant Sourire contracted a seasonal illness.
She needs to rest in quarantine.
Heart palpitations?
Due to intense fright.
Attendant Sourire has a high fever
and experiences difficulty talking.
In that case, Attendant Chun must move out.
Yes.
Attendant Sourire's illness has internal and external factors,
and can be infectious with the change of seasons.
I'm afraid if other concubines catch the disease...
Attendant Chun will move out then.
Since you diagnosed Attendant Sourire's illness,
you should continue to tend to her.
Your Majesty, I will spare no effort.
Starting tonight, the new concubines can
serve Your Majesty.
Would Your Majesty still prefer to visit Consort Fleur?
Are you probing my intentions?
I dare not speculate about Your Majesty's mind.
The Attendance Services will present the name tags.
Your Majesty, please turn over a name tag.
Where's the name tag for Attendant Sourire?
Your Majesty, the Imperial Infirmary reported this afternoon
that Attendant Sourire contracted a plague due to emotional distress.
She is required to rest in quarantine.
Emotional distress?
Consort Fleur granted Attendant Xia "Three Yards of Red"
in front of Attendant Sourire, Lady Shen, and Companion An.
Attendant Xia has become... paralyzed.
What did she do this for?
Attendant Xia was disrespectful and intended to beat a concubine.
But Consort Fleur's punishment was too harsh.
Attendant Xia should learn a lesson
about attempting to use violence in the palace.
Consort Fleur's maid, Fuzi, died in a well for unknown reasons.
And Attendant Sourire saw her dead body.
For unknown reasons?
What did Consort Fleur say?
She said Fuzi lost her footing,
but Jiang Fuhai believes there were other reasons.
Maids are from the Eight Banners.
Consort Fleur...
Keep investigating.
Attendant Sourire is sick ...
Noble Lady Shen and Companion An were not affected.
[Noble Lady Shen]
Congratulations, Noble Lady Shen.
My Lady, His Majesty selected your name tag tonight.
Among all the new concubines,
you are the first one to be favored by His Majesty.
Thank you, sir.
Lunar.
No need to thank me.
My Lady, you should get ready quickly
to serve His Majesty.
But... What...
This is Madam Liu. She prepares concubines for service.
Please let her go over the rules with you, My Lady.
You will soon be taken to the Hall of Mental Cultivation
by the Phoenix Carriage.
My Lady, await your blessings.
I will take my leave.
Take care, sir.
Your Majesty, Noble Lady Shen is here.
Carry her in.
Your Majesty.
My Lady, you like chrysanthemums,
so His Majesty gifted all these to you. How thoughtful!
That's the only flower we have in autumn.
Don't overthink.
But it's true. His Majesty cherishes you the most.
The new concubines moved in more than a month ago.
His Majesty hasn't given anyone else much attention.
You are not only most-summoned concubine, but also receive the most rewards.
You shouldn't be discussing this in broad daylight.
The white ones are called "Auspicious Spring Snow"
and the golden ones are "Cloud Soaring Dragon".
The two snuggling on one stem
resembles you and His Majesty.
Enough with the teasing!
His Majesty the Emperor.
Peace to Your Majesty.
What's so funny? Let me hear it.
- Rise.
- I thank Your Majesty.
How do you like the flowers?
I saw them in full bloom at the garden house,
so I had them sent to your palace.
I adore them. I thank Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, My Lady is very fond of chrysanthemums.
She is deeply thankful to your Majesty.
I can see that from the embroidery on your dress.
Why do you like chrysanthemums?
"The withered flowers still hold fragrance on the stem;
They never surrender or fall in the northern wind."
I like the flowers for their integrity.
You are well-read.
I didn't mean to show off. I seek Your Majesty's forgiveness.
I like that you read. Books teach us decorum.
Chrysanthemums are known for their perseverance.
But I most value their aloofness from the other spring flowers.
It endures loneliness so it can thrive in eternity.
I am thankful for Your Majesty's teaching.
If you like, I will have more chrysanthemums
selected and sent to you.
I know the garden house has worked hard to
cultivate some green chrysanthemums to bloom.
You will have all of them.
I thank Your Majesty.
The name of your chamber sounds like it belongs
to a scholar's classroom.
How boring.
Since you like the flowers,
I will name it the Chamber of Chrysanthemums for you.
I came today with a purpose in mind.
I want you to learn about housekeeping for the palace.
The trivial, the troublesome,
you should pay attention and learn them.
But I know nothing about housekeeping.
That's why you should learn.
You're intelligent and prudent.
I know that and appreciate it.
So I am entrusting you with this task.
Managing the palace is like running a household.
You will gradually become proficient.
Yes, I will do my best.
That's the spirit!
You can learn anything once you put your heart into it.
The Empress is not in good health
and Consort Fleur is too quick-tempered.
I appreciate your stable personality.
I hope one day you can help me manage the palace affairs.
My Lady, Madam Autumn is here.
Peace to My Lady.
Please stay in bed, My Lady.
Madam, what has led you to come here personally?
My Lady, Her Majesty has heard that
you are not recovering and became worried about you.
She sent me here to visit you.
I thank Her Majesty for her concern.
You look gaunt and tired.
What did the doctor say?
My Lady, it's time for medicine.
My Lady.
My Lady's weak constitution is still suffering
from her recent fright.
She's been taking the medicine three times a day
but not showing signs of recovery.
The herbs can treat illness of the body,
but there's no medicine for illness of the mind.
Attendant Summer's legs are no longer functional.
The imperial doctors said she can still live
but not walk anymore.
Consort Fleur said it's inconvenient for her to stay
in the Palace of Prolonging Happiness
and sent her to the Cold Palace.
It's a shame, but it's her own fault.
And you've been affected too.
I'm too timid. I don't blame Attendant Xia.
Of course, but you fell ill at the wrong time.
Noble Lady Shen has taken advantage of it
and become the newest favored concubine.
I'm not as blessed.
I can't compare to Noble Lady Shen's Heavenly favor.
But it would be my fault if I made
Her Majesty worried about me.
Rest well, My Lady.
I will return now and visit you another time.
Mr. Kang.
Yes.
Please escort Madam out.
I take my leave.
Attendant Sourire has the face of a flower but the heart of the mouse.
She's no more than the embroidered flowers
on a pillow: pretty, but useless.
She's new to the palace
and saw such bloodshed - how could she not be frightened?
That Companion An looks effete and timid.
But she didn't get scared or ill.
Consort Fleur's demeanor is nothing new to you.
But even though you are the Third Prince's mother,
when she came to pay respects,
you had to bow to her first.
Does Your Majesty blame me for being a coward?
But the Third Prince isn't cherished by His Majesty.
Nor does His Majesty value me, especially as I age.
I cannot compare to Consort Fleur's youth and beauty,
and her family's prominence.
You should look further into the future.
You have the Third Prince, after all.
We have lost my First Prince
and Empress Première's Second Prince.
The Third Prince is the eldest son now.
Your status is much more distinguished
than the childless Consort Fleur.
I understand that, but His Majesty doesn't like the Third Prince.
Then you must make it happen!
With a mother like you,
no wonder the Third Prince hasn't learned much.
But His Majesty hasn't stepped into my palace for months.
Your Highness, look.
There are plenty of chrysanthemums in the Imperial Garden
but they are not as stunning as ours.
Of course, the beauty of the flowers reflects the owner.
Our palace has the most beautiful Consort.
Of course we have the most beautiful flowers.
Did you rub honey on your mouth today,
to butter me up like this?
I have to slap my mouth
for making Her Highness frown.
But Your Highness, I only spoke the truth.
Your Highness, I've never seen green chrysanthemums before!
They are special indeed.
They must be in a hurry to deliver His Majesty's gifts to our palace.
If the flowers are for me, they can stop here.
We can look at them now.
Come over here!
Peace to Your Highness.
Rise.
Why are you walking so slowly?
Are my green chrysanthemums too heavy for your arms?
It must have taken a great deal of effort
to grow this rare flower.
Just leave them here.
Your Highness... the chrysanthemums ...
Speak.
They are for the Chamber of Chrysanthemums.
Then go.
I beg Your Highness's forgiveness.
Slap yourself.
It was all my fault!
[Chamber of Chrysanthemums]
The writing looks so nice!
My Lady, the new plaque looks nice.
His Majesty had it replaced it so quickly.
He holds you in a special place in his heart.
Don't say such things out loud.
Others will mock us.
Move faster!
Why is it taking so long? It's just a few pots of flowers.
I will have no chrysanthemums in my palace
ever again!
Move them, faster!
It is still early. Take your time, My Lady.
It's more comfortable to walk.
My bones are stiff from sitting in the sedan.
What's wrong with you?
My Lady, I was in a hurry to deliver water.
I meant no offense.
Forget it, Lunar. We have to go back and get changed quickly.
We can't be late to pay our respects.
Oh, Lady Shen arrived quite early today.
I'm late to pay my respects to Your Majesty.
I entreat Your Majesty's pardon.
Your respect is genuine.
It's all right if you're late occasionally.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Have a seat.
Your Majesty is very considerate.
But your indulgence may spoil Noble Lady Shen
and the harem's discipline.
Indeed.
Pardon my jesting, but are we exempt from paying
respects if we show "genuine respect" to Your Majesty?
Your Majesty, My Lady was late for a reason.
A eunuch splashed water on her dress,
so we went back to change it.
But she was still late.
She made a mistake and must bear the consequences.
Your Majesty, Lady Shen made a mistake
but she has always been diligent in her service to Your Majesty.
Please forgive her this time.
You are the head of Lady Shen's palace,
and thus responsible for failing to guide her.
Let's leave the matter as it is.
Fleur, how do you think we should resolve it?
Lady Shen grew conceited over her favor and disrespected the Empress.
This offense warrants a thirty-lash flogging.
But our kindness transcends the law.
Given that it's her first offense, Lady Shen will forfeit
her stipends for the next two months.
For setting a poor example, Estime should also suffer
the same punishment.
What does Your Majesty think?
Your Majesty, I am at fault and will accept my punishment.
But this matter does not involve Concubine Estime.
I hope Your Majesty will show leniency.
As Consort Fleur suggested,
I agree that a light punishment is enough.
It is the New Year in two months.
The forfeit will be one month instead.
I thank Your Majesty.
I will remember and never make this mistake again.
You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
You all must be tired. You may retire.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
I'll take my leave too, Your Majesty.
You didn't have to insist on a heavy punishment today.
What did Your Majesty think is suitable then?
You're like a sister to me in the imperial family.
Because you always have the heart to pay respects to me,
I do not mind what time you arrive.
So Your Majesty thinks I was too harsh on Noble Lady Shen?
Your Majesty is generous by nature.
But the palace is nothing like the estate
we lived in when the Emperor was still a prince.
His Majesty wanted me to assist in palace management
because he knows you are kind-hearted.
So leniency is balanced with strictness.
If I failed to do so, wouldn't I be breaking His Majesty's trust?
His Majesty requested your assistance
because he believes you are exemplary to all the other concubines.
In the future, I hope you can come early to pay respects.
I will remember Your Majesty's advice.
But His Majesty is considerate and
often insists that I sleep in.
May I ask Your Majesty whose order I shall obey?
We both serve His Majesty.
Naturally, we put His Majesty first.
Since Your Majesty has given clear instructions,
I will take my leave now.
I came to report to Your Majesty.
Speak.
As suspected, Fuzi was deliberately killed.
Really?
The bruises on her neck and forehead are evidence.
And Consort Fleur's displeasure was observed
when His Majesty talked to Fuzi that night.
Her behaviour is getting more and more audacious!
Report this truthfully to His Majesty.
Yes.
I need to see the records for the Attendance Services.
It has been sent here for Your Highness.
Lady Shen - twice this month,
and twice for Lady Fuca.
That's quite a lot.
Not at all compared to Your Highness.
But His Majesty has only visited the harem
seven times this month.
I have to "mend the windows before it rains."
In case they grow conceited over favor
and get out of control.
His Majesty values the unity between the Manchu and Han peoples.
Bring Lady Fuca here.
I'll teach her a lesson.
(Noble Lady Fuca)
His Majesty often says that Manchus and Hans are one family.
As a Manchu concubine, you must also know the Han script.
When His Majesty is writing,
you have to grind the ink by his side.
Grinding ink is an acquired skill.
You have to learn it properly.
Yes.
Everything I teach you is for your own good.
Grinding for only two hours is not enough.
There's still a long way to go.
Luobu Zangdan has revolted in Qinghai Province,
threatening the stability in the Northwest.
Zhang Tingyu,
who do you think is suitable for pacifying the rebellion?
Your Majesty, in terms of affinity and military deployment,
there is only one candidate.
Nian Gengyao.
Your Majesty is wise.
The influence of your brothers, Lord VIII and Lord IX,
has not been fully eliminated.
General Nian is the brother of Consort Fleur, and
has managed the military affairs in the West for a long time.
Therefore, he is the most suitable candidate in my opinion.
Nian Gengyao has indeed made
significant contributions to my throne,
but his power has grown unchecked in the Northwest.
The Deputy Commander, Yue Zhongqi
is a descendant of the great general Yue Fei.
He is knowledgeable about Northwestern affairs
and known as the Ever-Victorious General.
He is always modest and diligent.
Perhaps...
Very well. I hereby appoint Nian Gengyao as Pacification General-in-Chief,
and Yue Zhongqi as the Counselor-in-Chief.
They will proceed to Qinghai.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, Zhou Ninghai from the Palace of Earthly Honor has
brought you pastries from Her Highness Consort Fleur.
Let him leave the pastries.
Aye.
I remember receiving eastern pearls from Jilin.
You will send her the pearls personally.
Say that I commend her for
her thoughtful assistance in palace management.
Aye.
It's late now. You should rest early, My Lady.
I'm not tired today.
You're rarely in such good spirits.
Since you fell sick,
except for Lady Shen, Attendant Chun, and Companion An,
even the wild cats and dogs have stopped visiting.
These past few days, I've noticed that the palace maids and eunuchs seem listless.
When I give them instructions,
even Xiao-Yinzi started to talk back to me.
That's not surprising.
If they don't want to work, leave them be.
Yes.
Jade, do you hear that?
Someone's crying.
It's Xiao-Yunzi. He's on night duty in the corridor.
Let's go see him.
What is wrong? Why are you crying so sadly?
Please forgive me for disturbing you, My Lady.
We all feel joy and sorrow.
Shedding tears is hardly a crime.
Tell me, why are you crying?
My elder brother also works in the palace.
He's been gravely ill for over a month.
That's why I'm so worried about him.
We all "eat the five grains" and sickness can follow.
Not much work is needed here these days.
You can go and take care of your brother.
Thank you, My Lady!
My Lady, it's cold out here. Let's go inside.
It's late. You should rest early.
Your Majesty has been toiling with state affairs lately.
I had bird's nest soup prepared with lotus seeds
for Your Majesty. It can clear internal heat.
Please have some.
I appreciate your thoughtfulness.
Jiang Fuhai has reported Fuzi's death to Your Majesty.
The harem is infested with jealous rivalries.
I hope Your Majesty can enlighten me on what to do.
I know who you're referring to.
But jealousy is inevitable in the harem.
Without their affection for me,
there wouldn't be so many rivalries.
I don't have the heart to punish that.
You should patiently reconcile them.
Yes.
Bird's nest soup is a nourishing treat.
You should have some more supplements in the winter as well.
I thank Your Majesty.
By the way, is Attendant Sourire getting better?
Dr. Wenhas always been praised for his medical skills.
However, Attendant Sourire's condition has not improved.
Recovering from an illness is as slow as
reeling cocoons into silk.
The doctor said Attendant Sourire needs more time
to recuperate, given her weak constitution.
In that case, she'll recuperate peacefully.
Yes.
You should each take a look at yourselves.
Enough with your downcast faces!
Shifu [how apprentices address their master],
you should look at Attendant Sourire.
While the servants in other palaces look spirited,
we have no life here.
No life? I'm left with no pride!
Xiao-Youzi used to be nothing in the palace,
but now he sees himself as equal to me
since Lady Fuca is in favor.
That bastard isn't even good enough to carry my shoes!
It's all due to our mistress's incompetence!
She's been sick for two months.
From what Dr. Wen said the other day,
it sounded like her situation would last long.
Is this a fatal disease?
Nonsense!
Even if My Lady recovers, she'll still look unwell,
unable to gain His Majesty's favor.
We will become "the servants of the servants" in the palace.
The Palace of Pearl Jade is cursed.
It ruined Lady Parfum, and soon Attendant Sourire.
No, this palace can't be the living tomb
we're buried in.
Sir, we will follow your advice.
My advice is to be smarter.
Sir, it's your turn to be on shift today.
She's ill and inactive. Why bother?
But it's time to find another mistress to work for.
My Lady wanted to have some tea. Why is it taking so long?
I have to light the stove and boil the water first.
My Lady will have to wait.
Also, the Household Department didn't send
the tea allotted to her this month.
My Lady will only have hot water later.
I saw tea leaves in your cup yesterday.
How is there no tea left for My Lady?
Did you make all the tea for yourself?
This is the palace.
You need evidence when you make such claims.
You're not living at home anymore.
Violet.
Vermilion is My Lady's dowry maid.
You've been in the palace for a long time.
How can you be so disrespectful?
Make the tea now.
If the tea leaves have run out,
collect them from the Household Department.
If Attendant Sourire is like this, it's probably incurable.
Shifu, since you've gained favor from
Concubine Beauté, please let me follow you.
Mr. Kang, if you've found a good place to go,
why are you hiding it from My Lady?
We can celebrate it together.
She'll find out know sooner or later.
Let's go and see My Lady now.
My Lady.
My Lady, I can no longer stay in your service!
What happened? Calm down.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.